<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops on Thomas Tran Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://tranindigo.github.io/categories/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops on Thomas Tran Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tranindigo.github.io/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Images to AWS S3 Using Ruby on Rails and Multipart/Form-Data</title>
      <link>https://tranindigo.github.io/posts/streaming-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tranindigo.github.io/posts/streaming-images/</guid>
      <description>When dealing with image uploads in a web application, handling large files efficiently is crucial. Storing images in memory can lead to significant memory usage, especially with large or numerous files. These large files are waste of server resources, cause unnecessary computation, and if you read them into memory, can have great scalability concerns. Instead, you can stream images directly to AWS S3 using multipart/form-data to avoid memory bloat. This article will walk you through how to achieve this using Ruby on Rails.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS CloudWatch: Monitoring &amp; Alarms</title>
      <link>https://tranindigo.github.io/posts/aws-cloudwatch-monitoring-alarms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tranindigo.github.io/posts/aws-cloudwatch-monitoring-alarms/</guid>
      <description>AWS CloudWatch is a fully-managed service for monitoring AWS services and workloads. For websites, apps, and microservices that are entirely hosted on AWS, this is a great cloud logging solution.&#xA;As a fully-managed service, it is very easy to manage log retention periods, which can be configured on a per-group basis. By default, CloudWatch stores the log data indefinitely. Another advantage of CloudWatch is that it allows you to easily monitor host performance of AWS services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to AWS KMS: Envelope Encryption</title>
      <link>https://tranindigo.github.io/posts/an-introduction-to-aws-kms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tranindigo.github.io/posts/an-introduction-to-aws-kms/</guid>
      <description>AWS Key Management Service (KMS) is a fully-managed service allows you to create and manage cryptographic keys and control their use across a wide range of AWS services. This is useful because it allows you to centrally manage the encryption keys that control access to your data.&#xA;Features KMS is durable to make sure that your keys are never lost. KMS stores multiple copies of encrypted versions of your keys in systems that are designed for 99.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
